<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    
    <title>New York Trailheads</title>
    
    
    <description>This website is a virtual proof that I'm awesome</description>
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Hiking in Spring Mud Season</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Tips for Enjoying the Trails While Protecting the Environment Springtime is one of the most beautiful times to hit the trails, but it also presents a unique set of challenges for hikers. As the snow melts and the ground thaws, many trails become boggy, slippery, and muddy—making it more difficult...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/01/Hiking-in-Spring-Mud-Season</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/03/01/Hiking-in-Spring-Mud-Season</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graphite Range Community Forest</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Located in Wilton, NY, just north of Saratoga Springs, this trail system offers over 200 acres and 5 miles to explore. As the name implies, this land is the site of former graphite mines, the remnants of which you can see at various points. Currently, the land is owned by...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/18/Graphite-Range-Community-Forest</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025/01/18/Graphite-Range-Community-Forest</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colonie Town Park</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Nestled along the Mohawk River on the very northern edge of the town of Colonie, this park offers trails meandering through the woods, a historic covered bridge, playgrounds, picnic areas, boat launch, and a pool that's open during the summer season. The entrance is located off Schermerhorn Road, not far...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024/02/19/Colonie-Town-Park</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/02/19/Colonie-Town-Park</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capital Region First Day Hikes 2024</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          For outdoor enthusiasts, nothing sets the tone for a new year better than a chance to take a hike! Several local parks and nature organizations have planned First Day Hikes, where you can join others on an outdoor trek. In this article, we'll provide an overview of hikes you can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/27/Capital-Region-First-Day-Hikes-2024</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/12/27/Capital-Region-First-Day-Hikes-2024</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Crossings of Colonie</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          As the second largest park in the town of Colonie, The Crossings offers a peaceful oasis in the midst of a crowded suburban area just outside of Albany. With open fields, wooded sections, and a decently sized pond, you can explore a 3.25 mile trail loop around the park, with...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/10/28/The-Crossings-of-Colonie</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/10/28/The-Crossings-of-Colonie</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bradley's Lookout</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Bradley's Lookout Officially opened by the Lake George Land Conservancy in 2020, the trail to Bradley's Lookout leads to a beautiful overlook of Lake George with less than a mile's hike one way. This trail starts from the same trailhead as The Pinnacle in Bolton Landing, and it can easily...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/10/21/Bradleys-Lookout</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/10/21/Bradleys-Lookout</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adirondack Hiking Challenges</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          While any excursion into the woods can be fun, and you don't need to have a specific goal to enjoy a day outdoors, working through a hiking challenge can be a great way to inspire a family to get outside or fulfill that &quot;completionist&quot; desire deep down. There are options...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/10/07/Adirondack-Hiking-Challenges</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/10/07/Adirondack-Hiking-Challenges</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Severance Hill</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          While trail guides seem to vary in opinion as to whether this is a &quot;hill&quot; or a &quot;mountain,&quot; there's no denying that this is hike provides an enjoyable short jaunt through classic Adirondack woods to a beautiful view over Schroon Lake. While it was a foggy morning on the day...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/09/Severance-Hill</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/09/09/Severance-Hill</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>July 4 Fireworks in the Capital Region &amp; Adirondacks</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Going to a fireworks show is a classic Independence Day activity, and upstate New York has plenty of options to offer. Here's a rundown of places you can go in the greater Capital Region and Adirondacks to see fireworks around July 4, 2023. Tri-City ValleyCats Game: June 29 The ValleyCats...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/24/July-4-Fireworks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/06/24/July-4-Fireworks</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Navigate with a Compass While Hiking</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Hiking is a great way to enjoy nature, explore new places, and stay fit. However, hiking also comes with some risks, such as getting lost or injured. That's why it's important to have some basic navigation skills and tools when you hit the trails. Pictured: SUUNTO A-10 Compass, a great...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/18/How-to-Use-a-Compass-While-Hiking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/03/18/How-to-Use-a-Compass-While-Hiking</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swift Wetland Preserve</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          One of many &quot;pocket preserves&quot; maintained by the Mohawk Hudson Land Conservancy, the Swift Wetland Preserve offers a taste of nature in the midst of suburban Delmar. One entrance is located across from Bethlehem High School on Delaware Avenue, while a second entrance with a small parking area can be...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/20/Swift-Wetland-Preserve</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/20/Swift-Wetland-Preserve</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capital Region Sledding Hills</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          For kids of all ages, few activities are more fun after a fresh snowfall than jumping on a sled and riding down a hill at top speed. Thankfully, the Capital Region has no shortage of hills for those looking for some classic winter fun. In this article, we're listing a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/09/Capital-Region-Sledding-Hills</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023/02/09/Capital-Region-Sledding-Hills</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Schuyler Flatts Cultural Park</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Located in the village of Menands, this tranquil 43-acre park contains a 3/4 mile trail loop as well as a connection to the Mohawk Hudson Bikeway. Originally owned by the renowned Schuyler family during the colonial era, this location was the site of a mansion and farm, also serving as...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/12/Schuyler-Flatts-Cultural-Park</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/11/12/Schuyler-Flatts-Cultural-Park</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fisher Trail</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Opened in October 2022, the Fisher Trail crosses land owned by the Mohawk Hudson Land Conservancy, ultimately connecting to established trails at the Five Rivers Environmental Education Center. The first half-mile of the Fisher Trail is designed as an accessible trail, starting with a boardwalk and leading to a wide,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/05/Fisher-Trail</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/11/05/Fisher-Trail</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bender Melon Farm Preserve</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          After a lengthy battle to keep this former farm from development, the Mohawk Hudson Land Conservancy purchased this plot of land in 2020. Covering 175 acres, this preserve contains a mix of woods, fields, and wetlands. Various trail loops traverse close to three miles all together throughout this preserve. Additionally,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/29/Bender-Melon-Farm-Preserve</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/10/29/Bender-Melon-Farm-Preserve</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Little Island (New York City)</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Little Island is a beautifully constructed slice of green in the midst of the concrete and metal of downtown Manhattan. If you're visiting New York City and have some time to spare, take a moment to stroll around this free-to-visit park, located near Chelsea Market and across from the High...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/27/little-island-nyc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/08/27/little-island-nyc</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skidmore North Woods</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Skidmore College, in Saratoga Springs, generously allows the public to walk the trails of its North Woods area. The trail system here covers around 150 acres with approximately 3.5 miles of walking trails throughout. Trail surfaces vary from gravel to dirt, with some minor elevation change. There are a few...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/06/Skidmore-North-Woods</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/08/06/Skidmore-North-Woods</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Baker Mountain</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Located just outside the village of Saranac Lake, this straight-up-and-down hike offers a rewarding view of the High Peaks after a short (but steep) climb. Parking is on Forest Hill Avenue (Rte. 3) right along Moody Pond. Please be very careful to observe all parking signs, as the town is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/Baker-Mountain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/08/14/Baker-Mountain</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Van Dyke Preserve</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          One of many Mohawk Hudson Land Conservancy &quot;pocket preserves&quot; in Albany's suburbs, the Van Dyke Preserve offers a 1-mile loop through the woods, with much of the trail going alongside the Philippin Kill. The trailhead is found just south of the Bethlehem Central High School off Van Dyke Road. A...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/06/Van-Dyke-Preserve</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/03/06/Van-Dyke-Preserve</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Schiffendecker Farm Preserve</title>
        
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ New York Trailheads ]]></dc:creator>
        
        <description>
          
          Located in Glenmont, just south of Albany, this preserve offers just over a mile of trails through a wooded ravine preserved from development, while surrounded by suburban shopping centers. You won't necessarily feel far from civilization, but you'll venture far enough into the woods to be able to enjoy the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/18/Schiffendecker-Farm-Preserve</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/01/18/Schiffendecker-Farm-Preserve</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
